Hello, and welcome to Lesson 31 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，这里是 Wolfram U的微积分入门，第31课
The topic for this lesson is average value of a function.
本次课程的主题是 函数的均值
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
让我们从本课的简要概述开始
Let’s say you have a list of numbers like over here,
假设有一个像这样的数列
and you want to work out their average value.
你想求他们的均值
Of course what you do is just add the numbers
当然 只需要把数字加起来
and then divide by the number of numbers,
然后除以数字个数
which is 10 in this case, and you get back the answer.
这里是 10 然后你就能得到答案
You also have a function called Mean in the Wolfram Language
在 Wolfram 语言中 还有一个称为 Mean 的函数
which does just the same thing for you,
做的是一件事
and you get back the same answer.
得到同一个答案
Now let’s say instead of a list of values,
现在说说不是数列的时候
you had a function like the one shown over here.
有一个像这里一样的函数
Here’s a plot of the function.
这是函数图像
The question is can we work out
问题是我们能否求得
the average value of such a function?
这个函数的均值
The answer is yes.
答案是肯定的
Here’s some intuition.
这是直觉
Let’s say your function runs from a to b.
假设函数在 a 和 b 之间
You break the interval into n subintervals,
将区间分为 n 个子区间
take a sample point for each subinterval
在每个字区间中取一个采样点
and then work out the average value like over here.
然后计算这的均值
Now we want to rewrite it as a Riemann sum,
现在我们想改写为黎曼和的形式
so the n over here can be thought of as being related to Δx,
所以这里的 n 可以认为与 Δx 有关
the length of each subinterval.
这是子区间长度
So  Δx is (b – a)/n, and hence n is (b – a)/Δx.
因此 Δx 是 (b – a)/n 并且得 n 是 (b – a)/Δx
You can rewrite the average in a slightly different form
你可以用略有不同的形式重写平均值
in which it’s clear that if you now let n go to ∞
很明显 如果现在让 n 趋向于 ∞
so you’ve got very small subintervals,
所以子区间很小
then what you get back is the integral
那么你得到积分
divided by the length of the interval.
除以区间的长度
That’s the average value of a function.
这就是函数的均值
It’s the integral of the function over an interval
他是在一个区间上的积分
divided by the length of the interval.
除以区间长度
Let’s say in our example, if you want to work out the average value,
假设对我们的例子 你要算均值
you simply find the integral from 0 to 5 and then divide by 5,
只需计算0到5之间的积分 然后除以5
and you get back the answer.
就能得到答案
Okay. Now a much deeper fact is
好 更深层的事实是
something called the mean value theorem, which says that
称为均值定理的东西
if you have a continuous function on an interval,
如果函数在区间上连续
then there is at least one number c in that interval
那么在区间中至少存在一个点 c
such that the value of the function is equal to the average value.
使得此点的函数值就是平均值
That should remind you of the mean value theorem for derivatives,
这会让你想到微分均值定理
which was the same thing,
这是一回事
but now for integrals over intervals and areas rather than slopes.
但是现在是针对的是区间上的积分和面积而不是斜率
If you multiply both sides by b – a,
如果将两边都乘以 b – a
what you get on the left-hand side is just the area of a rectangle
左边得到的是一个矩形的面积
with height f(c) and length b – a,
高是 f(c) 长为 b – a
and the right-hand side is the integral.
然后右边是这个积分
Here is a visual interpretation of the whole thing.
这是整个事情的可视化描述
Let’s say that this is your curve,
来看这条曲线
and now you have the area under the curve, and that’s the rectangle.
现在有曲线下的面积 这就是矩形
Now there’s a bit of area that’s common over here,
现在这里又一些公共区域
and then a bit over here which only belongs to the rectangle
然后在这里有些点只属于矩形
and a bit that only belongs to the curve,
还有些点只属于曲线
and what we’re saying over here is that the area of this rectangle
我们说在这个地方有 这个矩形的面积
is equal to the area under the curve.
等于曲线下的面积
That’s quite a remarkable theorem.
这是个相当了不起的定理
It’s very deep and shows you how powerful calculus is.
他非常深刻 并且展现了微积分的力量
We’re able to reduce the area under a curve
我们能够分解曲线下的面积
to the area of a rectangle,
移到矩形区域
which is the simplest thing one might think about in areas.
这是人们能想到的最简单的事情
Okay. As an application, here’s a function,
好 作为应用 这有一个函数
and you want to find a value in the interval –2 to 3
要找一个在区域 -2 到 3 之间的值
such that the function value is equal to
使得这个函数的均值等于
the average value over that interval.
他在这个区域上的均值
Now because the function is continuous, it’s a polynomial,
由于函数是连续的 他是个多项式
so you can certainly apply the theorem, the mean value theorem.
所以当然可以应用这个定理 即均值定理
Let’s say you want to do that.
假设你要这样做
You solve the equation f[c] equal to the average value,
解这个方程 f[c] 等于 均值
and when you do that, you get back an answer.
等你这么做完 就能得到答案
Here’s a plot which shows the point at which
这张图 显示了
the average value is actually retained.
这个均值实际上是有的
That’s the mean value theorem in action.
这就是均值定理在起作用
But the main point is that sometimes you can get
但是要点是有时候你可以得到
more than one point at which the average value is retained.
不止一个点 这些点的值都是均值
Here’s an example.
这有一个例子
You have a function.
这个函数
You try and work out the average value, and then work out
试着算一下均值 然后得到
the point at which you want to check whether
这些点 你要检查是否
the average value equals the function value.
均值等于函数值
You get two points now, and here’s a picture which says
你现在得到两个点 这张图上面说
that you really have two points at which
你真的有两个点
the average value is attained.
能取到均值
As an application of these ideas,
作为这些思想的应用
here’s a temperature for a city t hours after noon.
这是 中午 t 小时后 城市的温度
You plot the temperate from 1pm to 3am,
画出从 1pm 到 3am 的温度图像
and the question is, is there a time at which the temperature
问题是 是否有有这么个时间当时的温度
equals the average temperature?
就是一天的平均温度
The answer is yes.
答案是肯定的
Just solve the equation and you get back that c is about 8.57.
只需解方程 就能得到 c 约是 8.57
That’s in hours, so that means at around 8:34pm,
以小时为单位 这意味着晚上 8:34 左右
the temperature will be equal to the average temperature
此时温度就是平均温度
over the time period.
在这一段时间中的
As another application, let’s look at a car on a highway.
另一个应用是 来看一下高速公路上的汽车
Here is the velocity of the car, and you want to find
这是汽车的速度 要算
the average velocity over the time period.
这段时间里的平均速度
What you do is you simply integrate
你要做的就是简单的积分
and divide by the time interval.
除以时间区间
Here’s a plot which shows clearly that
这张图清楚的表明
the average value is attained at two different points,
平均值能够在不同的两个点取到
so the average velocity is attained twice in the interval.
所以平均速度能取到两次在区域内
That brings me to the end of this lesson,
这节课到此为止
but the main point for today is that with integration,
但是今天的重点是积分
you can find the average value of a function over an interval.
你可以找到某个区间内的函数的平均值
That average value is given by the integral
均值的计算由这个积分
divided by the length of the interval.
除以区间长度得到
The mean value theorem is a very powerful theorem
均值定理是非常有力的一个定理
which says that if you have a continuous function,
他表明如果有一个连续函数
then it takes on its average value at least once—
那他至少能取到一次他的均值
could be more than once, but at least once—in the interval.
在区间内可能不止取到一次 但是至少一次
Of course once you have this very powerful theorem,
当然一旦有了这个非常强大的定理
you could apply it to temperatures or velocities
你可以应用到温度和速度上
or all kinds of other fillable phenomena.
或者其他的可填充的现象中
You have the mean value theorem, which tells you that
均值定理 告诉你
the area under the curve is equal to the area of a certain rectangle.
曲线下的面积等于某个矩形的面积
That’s a very powerful theorem for calculus.
对于微积分这是非常强大的一个定理
In the next lesson we’ll talk about approximate values of integrals,
在下一课中 我们将讨论积分的近似
but for now, do review this lesson,
但现在 请复习本课中
go over the idea for the mean value
求平均值的思想
and I’ll see you next time.
我们下次见
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
本节课到此为止，再见